In this lecture we are going to discuss the 7th architecture consideration
that you need to think about while building production ready rag based applications.
And that is rag evaluation.
So bedrock evaluations can be used to evaluate the performance of bedrock models and
knowledge bases as well as models and retrieval augmented generation sources outside of Amazon
bedrock. So this is important. In one of the previous lectures we already saw how
Amazon bedrock evaluations can be used for evaluating the performance of bedrock models.
But it can also be used for evaluating the performance of bedrock knowledge bases.
Now the important thing is not only does Amazon bedrock evaluations help you evaluate the
models on Amazon bedrock and bedrock knowledge bases. But you can also have the models and
rag based sources outside of Amazon bedrock. So let's say you have built a rag based solution
using some of the open source frameworks like Langchin etc. You can go and get that dataset
maybe with the prompt response generated by the rag system and reference response.
And then you can have it evaluated on Amazon bedrock evaluation.
Okay. So next so Amazon bedrock can be evaluated based on different
performance metrics for a model and the correctness of knowledge base in retrieving
information and generating response. So it provides you option of selecting different
performance metrics to evaluate the responses from your knowledge base.
Now let's take a look at the steps you need to follow for Amazon bedrock evaluations.
So first is you choose your evaluator model. So the evaluation would be done by a large
language model. So you can select let's say cloud from entropic or Amazon novapro and so on.
So you can select your evaluator model then you define the inference source. So if you have built
your rag system in bedrock knowledge bases you can select that from the dropdown or you can
also bring your own dataset where you bring in the prompt reference response and the output
that has been generated. So if it's outside bedrock knowledge bases.
Then you can evaluate along two broad areas retrieve or retrieve and generate.
So we discussed that it evaluates either along retrieve or retrieve and generate.
So for retrieval you will see there are two metrics context coverage and context relevance.
So context coverage basically looks at the rag response and what is there in the data source
and determines what is the context coverage. Then it also looks at the context relevance
whether the answer that's been generated is irrelevant to the user query. Then the second
metric you can choose will be along retrieval and generation. So here there are a lot of different
metrics and we have seen a lot of them previously as well. So correctness completeness, healthfulness,
logical coherence, faithfulness and then it also covers some of the metrics around responsible
AI. So you can see a harmful as stereotyping and refusal. Then you have upload prompt dataset.
So this is valid if you are doing the evaluation of a rag system outside bedrock knowledge bases
and then finally you have the inference and evaluation that will be done by Amazon bedrock
evaluation and then finally you can see the results. Okay, so that's pretty much it from this
lecture. I'll see you in the next lecture. Thank you.